RG 077, Bipartisan Commission on State Tax Revenue and Related Fiscal Policy
Connecticut State Library
Bipartisan Commission on State Tax Revenue and Related Fiscal Policy records
1982-1983
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Bipartisan Commission on State Tax Revenue and Related Fiscal Policy
3 cubic feet
In 1981, the General Assembly created this bipartisan commission to “conduct a study and undertake an analysis of state tax revenue, state tax laws, administration of state tax laws, and state fiscal policy in relation to tax revenue.”
RG077
1983-001
Historical Note
In November 1981, a Special Session of the General assembly created a bipartisan commission to "conduct a study and undertake an analysis of state tax revenue, state tax laws, administration of state tax laws and state fiscal policy in relation to tax revenue." The Special Session also directed the commission to evaluate "(1) the existing tax structure in the state, (2) all sources of revenue available, (3) alternative methods of providing revenue to meet the anticipated needs of the state and (4) current federal and state fiscal policy and the impact of such policy on the tax structure of the state."
The 27 member commissioner was appointed in March 1982 and began holding meetings in April. Senate Majority Leader Richard F. Schneller of Essex served as chairperson, and Dr. William McEachern served as Staff Director. The commission and its subcommittees met to hear testimony from fiscal experts and examine statistical tables and charts prepared by the staff. The commission then issued preliminary findings, recommendations, and options and invited public comment by mail and through five public hearings held in November and December throughout the state. On December 9, 10, and 11, the commission met to develop final recommendations. The final report submitted to Governor O'Neill was dated January 1, 1983.
Scope and Content
Includes transcripts of meetings, sound recordings of public hearings, the final report, public comments, background information and administrative files.
Related Material
RG 045, State Revenue Task Force, 1969 - 1971
RG 047, Special Tax Commission, 1933 - 1935
RG 086, Governor's Commission on Tax Reform, 1972
RG 087, Connecticut Tax Study Commission, 1966 - 1967
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Bipartisan Commission on State Tax Revenue and Related Fiscal Policy
Persons:
McEachern, William; Schneller, Richard F
Subjects:
Connecticut -- Appropriations and expenditures; Connecticut. Bipartisan Commission on State Tax Revenue and Related Fiscal Policy -- Records and correspondence; Finance, Public -- Connecticut; Fiscal policy -- Connecticut; Taxation -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Printouts; Reports; Sound recordings; Transcripts
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
The State Archives received these three boxes on January 17, 1983.
Container List
- Records, 1982-1983
  - 1. Transcripts of meetings, 1982 April 2 - December 10 (Box 1)
    Arranged chronologically.
  - 2. Sound recordings of public hearings, 1982 November 29 - December 6 (Box 2)
    Tape cassettes of proceedings in communities.
    - Waterbury, 1982 November 29 (Box 2)
    - Stamford, 1982 November 30 (Box 2)
    - Norwich, 1982 December 1 (Box 2)
    - Hartford, 1982 December 2 (Box 2)
    - New Haven, 1982 December 6 (Box 2)
  - 3. Final report, 1983 January 1 (Box 2)
    Original typed copy of final report, with transmittal letter signed by chairman, table of contents, text and appendices. Copy of published final report, executive summary of final report, and preliminary findings.
  - 4. Public comments, 1982 November - December (Box 2)
    Written comments from the public on preliminary findings and recommendations.
    Unarranged.
  - 5. Background information distributed to commission members prior to meetings, 1982 May 7 - November 12 (Box 1)
  - 6. Dictation material, 1982 April 2 - December 10 (Box 3)
    Dictabelts, dictating cassettes, belt and cassette logs, and some rough transcripts used to prepare typed transcripts of meetings.
  - 7. General background and administrative files, 1982 April - December (Box 1)
    Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Alternates (Box 1)
    - Budget (Box 1)
    - Commission: Budget (Box 1)
    - Commission: Guidelines (Box 1)
    - Commission: Members (Box 1)
    - Commission: Project Director (Box 1)
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Expenditures: May 7th meeting slides, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Meeting notices and agendas (Box 1)
    - Minority reports (Box 1)
    - Minutes (Box 1)
    - OFA: 81 Tax changes and description of revenue (Box 1)
    - Originals (Box 1)
    - Preliminary report, tax exemption subcommittee (Box 1)
    - Property tax: Exemptions (Box 1)
    - Public hearings (Box 1)
    - Revenue Services tax receipts (Box 1)
    - Subcommittees (Box 1)
    - Tax administration (Box 1)
    - [Untitled] (Box 1)
  - 8. Computer printouts (Box 1)
    Statistical tables and charts.